<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Quick tips by Anubhav Srivastava]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal quick tips for Web Developers]]></description><link>http://devtips.theanubhav.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 05:23:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Stick your notes on any site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Take your own notes for a page of a site or anywhere on the web via Firefox Addon. The notes persist for that site for future use. ]]></description><link>http://devtips.theanubhav.com/posts/stick-your-notes-on-any-site</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://devtips.theanubhav.com/posts/stick-your-notes-on-any-site</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 18:05:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Sticky Notes&lt;/code&gt; is a browser extension that helps in taking notes for a site that too on the site itself. The notes persis for future use and can be used to chalk down notes or important points for that page/site. These draggable notes can be placed anywhere on the page, where ever it may be relevant. You can create notes via context menu or using shortcut keys. Usage guide is mentioned in the extension page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Sticky Notes&lt;/code&gt; by Hiroki Kumamoto is available as &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stickynotes/imcecnigpdchlakcljkjjhddmilnmcji&quot;&gt;Chrome Extension&lt;/a&gt; and [&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/sticky-notes/&quot;&gt;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/sticky-notes/&lt;/a&gt;) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use it to chalk down action items from PRDs, Design specification, etc that I work upon. It is really helpful on github pages to note points for that repository like configuration option, current version which I am using for update purpose, pull-request/issue notes, or common usage cli command. I usually end up forgetting cli options for various tools, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ytdl-org/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt;, and pin frequent cli commands for them on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/sticky-notes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official Site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kumabook.tokyo/stickynotes/&quot;&gt;Sticky Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Become a better developer, one tab at a time.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Gain new developer skills every time you open a New Tab! Choose which programming languages you want to get better at in options and get smarter every time you open a New Tab. All you need is 30 seconds to read and understand snippets of code and improve your knowledge.]]></description><link>http://devtips.theanubhav.com/posts/become-a-better-developer-30-seconds-of-knowledge/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://devtips.theanubhav.com/posts/become-a-better-developer-30-seconds-of-knowledge/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 18:05:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Gain new developer skills every time you open a New Tab! Choose which programming languages you want to get better at in options and get smarter every time you open a New Tab. All you need is 30 seconds to read and understand snippets of code and improve your knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;30 seconds of Knowledge&lt;/code&gt; is available as &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/30-seconds-of-knowledge/mmgplondnjekobonklacmemikcnhklla&quot;&gt;Chrome Extension&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/30-seconds-of-knowledge/&quot;&gt;Firefox addons&lt;/a&gt; will help you get small random snippets from JS, CSS, HTML, React, Python, PHP, Ruby, C++, Ramda, etc with this list increasing with every new update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time you open a New Tab, you will get a random code Snippet from a library of ~900 snippets. One can save the snippet for future reference or whenever in hurry. Also, one can choose the language/framework he wants to get snippets of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official Site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://30secondsofknowledge.com/&quot;&gt;30 seconds of Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Starting to chalk down small tips]]></title><description><![CDATA["A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step" is a common saying that originated from a famous Chinese proverb. So here is a dedicated place on the web to talk and chalk out some of my personal small tips for developers. ]]></description><link>http://devtips.theanubhav.com/posts/starting-to-chalk-down-small-tips/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://devtips.theanubhav.com/posts/starting-to-chalk-down-small-tips/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 18:05:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;“A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step” is a common saying that originated from a famous Chinese proverb. So here is a dedicated place on the web to talk and chalk out some of my personal small tips for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After blogging few post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://theanubhav.com&quot;&gt;theAnubhav.com&lt;/a&gt;, I realised that it took quite a time to write down article in detail. And most of the blog were always in mind but due to slow pace of thoroughly writing down, few of them never saw the light of day. Though I had lot of small findings/topic to tell the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here it is, dedicated site to just write down small stuffs that relates and adds as a tip to fellow web developers. Not expecting it to be a daily article but expecting it to be at least a weekly one. Would try to keep each post to point and concise so that it acts as a tip and does not become a tutorial/theory. Hoping for best! Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>